准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
倒霉海绵宝宝
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
早安  闹钟
Good morning, alarm clock
到底要选哪个呢
Choices, choices
裤子穿反了
Pants are a little twisted around
差点忘了我的幸运领带夹
Almost forgot my lucky tie clip
我准备好了
I'm ready
小姐  让我来帮你
Young lady, allow me
你啊
Oh, you
早安  海绵宝宝
Morning, SpongeBob
早安  下水道修理工
Good morning, Sewer Man
好个幸运儿
There goes one lucky boy
停
明天见  小可爱
See you tomorrow, sweetie
完了
Whoopsie
早安  章鱼哥
Good morning, Squidward
你今天一大早怎么精力这么旺盛
And why are you so peppy this morning?
因为今天是我的幸运日
Because today is my lucky day
都是我幸运领带夹的功劳
thanks to my lucky tie clip
你领带夹不是天天都戴着吗
Don't you wear that tie clip every day?
每天都是我的幸运日
Every day is my lucky day
才没运气这回事
Luck isn't real
都是你在脑袋里乱想
It's all in your head
章鱼哥  不相信运气会倒大霉的
Squidward, it's unlucky not to believe in luck
抱歉  章鱼哥先生
Sorry, Mr. Squidward
没看到你
Didn't see you there
一份豪华腌椰菜蟹黄堡  完美特制
One Krabby Patty pickle deluxe, perfectly prepared
我倒要锐评一下
I'll be the judge of that
我很想投诉
I want to complain
但也太好吃了
But it's too delectable
你
How?
你怎么做到这么完美的
How did you accomplish such perfection?
应该是我运气好吧
Guess I'm just lucky
第二天早上
准备好再过一个幸运日了吗  小蜗
Ready to start another lucky day, Gary?
我的幸运领带夹呢
Where's my lucky tie clip?
不在这
Not here
不在
No
没有
Nuh-uh
No
我的幸运领带夹不见了
My lucky tie clip is missing
不好
Oh no
上班要迟到了
I'm late for work
等会再找吧
I'll search for it later
抱歉
Sorry
我今天来晚了
I was running late today
天啊  太倒霉了
Jeez, what bad luck
交出钱包
Give me your wallet
动作快
Make it snappy
明天见  小可爱
See you tomorrow, sweetie
完了
Whoopsie
热狗
Hot dog
来买热
Get your hot--
你是怎么了
What happened to you?
我幸运领带夹丢了
I lost my lucky tie clip
现在所有事都出了错
and now everything is going wrong
根本就没运气这回事
There's no such thing as luck
你的破领带夹跟这玩意一点关系都没
Your dumb tie clip has nothing to do with it
章鱼哥又可怜又天真
Poor naive Squidward
锅铲抽筋了
Spatula cramp
此处点餐
请问有没有什么推荐
Do you have any recommendations?
有
Yeah
去别家吃饭
Eat somewhere else
建议得十分绝妙
Excellent advice
谢谢  小伙子
Thank you, young man
小费
A tip?
今天一定是我幸运日
Must be my lucky day
并不是说我信了那套胡话
Not that I believe in that nonsense
一份蟹黄堡套餐
One Krabby Patty combo
汽水没气了  薯条太油了
The soda is flat, the fries are oily
而且蟹黄堡没味道
and the Krabby Patty is bland
没味道
B-b-b-bland?
你是怎么了  小子
What's the matter with you, boyo?
我倒大霉了  蟹老板
I'm bad luck, Mr. Krabs
倒霉
Bad luck
Bad luck?
蟹堡王的生意好坏全靠运气
The restaurant business runs on luck
倒霉一来  蟹堡王就要完蛋了
If bad luck sets in, the Krusty Krab is doomed
全都出去
Everyone out
出去出去出去
Out, out, out, out, out
我得烧点干海草
I got to burn some dried kelp
把这里的坏运气全净化了
and cleanse this joint of any bad mojo
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
章鱼哥
Squidward
你们今天放假
Take the day off
放假
Day off?
不要
No
好耶
Yes
但愿我的好运气
I hope my good luck
转移到了有需要的人身上
went to someone who needed it
一根头发
A hair?
海绵宝宝的好运气多半转到我身上了
Maybe I'm getting SpongeBob's good luck
派大星
Hey, Patrick
海绵宝宝
Hey, SpongeBob
没事吧
You OK?
我幸运领带夹丢了
I lost my lucky tie clip
现在我全天下最倒霉
I am now the unluckiest person alive
能不能来抱一个
Can I have a hug?
不用  谢谢
No, thank you
无论如何我都不碰你
I wouldn't touch you with a 10-foot pole
十 尺 长 杆
可不能让你的霉运传染给我
I don't want your bad luck to rub off on me
我该怎么办
What am I going to do?
不然你就再找个护身符吧
Why don't you find a new lucky charm?
好办法
Great idea
谢了  派大星
Thanks, Patrick
没你我都不知道该怎么办了
I don't know what I'd do without you
我的幸运十一尺长杆
my lucky 11-foot pole
幸运  幸运
Lucky, lucky
四叶海草
A four-leaf kelp
这种东西可幸运了
They're really lucky
新建了条公路
A new freeway?
这就不幸运了
That's not lucky
一只海兔脚
A sea bunny's foot
更幸运了
They're extra lucky
除非脚还长在海兔子身上
Unless it's still attached to the sea bunny
抱歉
Sorry
章鱼哥
Squidward?
某些人运气好得不得了  海绵宝宝
Some people have all the luck, SpongeBob
反正好的不是你
just not you
我的领带夹
My tie clip?
原来我整天都带着
I had it with me all day?
就跟章鱼哥说的一个样
It was just like Squidward said
章鱼哥  你说得对
Hey, Squidward, you were right
运气都在我脑袋里
Luck was all just in my head
这个纯金领带夹再也用不上了
I don't need this solid gold lucky tie clip
不过保险一点也无妨
But it never hurts to be on the safe side
章鱼哥  我的好运气回来了
Hey, Squidward, my good luck is back
回到我脑袋里了
Back in my head
等下
Hold on
如果海绵宝宝的运气回来了  那
If SpongeBob's luck is back, then--
完了
Oh, no
真倒霉
Just my luck
睡魔降临
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
指导总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
水母田
你来捉  派大星
You got him, Patrick
你要被我捉到了  水母
You're mine now, jelly
一觉之后
我睡了多久
How long was I out?
大概一星期
About a week
破纪录了
A new record
没错  熟能生巧
Yeah, it's all in the old wrist
睡一整天最能消耗精力了
Nothing like a day of napping to tucker you out
晚安  台灯先生
Good night, Mr. Lamp
还睡不着
Not sleeping yet
换这个姿势躺试试
Maybe if I lay this way
我还是坐等变困好了
I guess I'll just sit up and wait to get sleepy
连续24小时睡不着之后
已经等睡着等了一整天了
I've been waiting to sleep all day
时间早都到斑点半了
It's already half past a freckle
还是看看海绵宝宝在干嘛好了
Guess I'll see what SpongeBob's doing
要来玩吗
Want to hang out?
派大星  是你啊
Patrick, it's you
这么晚来干嘛
What are you doing here so late?
我睡不着
I can't sleep
来做事吧
Let's do stuff
行吧
OK, sure
可我四小时后就必须要起床
but I have to be up in four hours
那就好
Perfect
你居然要打赢我了
I can't believe you're beating me
你又赢了
You win again?
好吧
All right
三百局两百胜
Best 200 out of 300
谁第一个挖到石头滩  谁就赢
First one to dig to rock bottom wins
派大星  虽然好玩归好玩
Patrick, this is really fun and all
可我真得睡觉了
but I need to get to bed
可我还是睡不着
But I still can't sleep
派大星  你一定得快点去睡觉
Patrick, you've got to get some sleep and fast
不然会出幻觉的
or else you could start seeing things
等等
Wait
看见东西
我现在就出幻觉了
I'm seeing things now
房子
House
地面
Ground
天空
Sky
快让幻觉停下来  海绵宝宝
Make it stop, SpongeBob
停下来
Make it stop
放心  兄弟
Don't worry, pal
我会帮你
I'll help you get to--
是我睡觉才对
That's my sleep
睡着
Sleep
你就只需要盖好被子  喝点热牛奶
All you need is a good tucking in and some warm milk
再来点菊花茶
And some chamomile tea
听我最爱的催眠曲
And my favorite lullaby
海绵宝宝  我还是睡不着
SpongeBob, I still can't sleep
看来只能用传统办法解决了
Looks like I'll have to do this the old-fashioned way
我还很清醒
I'm still awake
还是很清醒
Still awake
好像能行
I think it's working
不行
No
万不得已也只能动杀手锏了
I didn't want to do this, but I'm down to my last resort
嗨  章鱼哥
Hi, Squidward
派大星
Patrick
你三更半夜来干什么
what could you possibly want at this hour of the night?
我要听你的生平事迹
I need to hear your life story
果然是要来犯傻
Just as I thought, an idiotic--
什么
what?
你要听我的生平事迹吗
You need to hear my life story?
对
Yep
你这么突然
Well, it's such short notice
我完全没准备啊
I don't have anything prepared
就只准备了这本草稿
except this rough manuscript
章鱼哥
八条腿八条命
第一卷
名叫
I call it
章鱼哥  八条腿八条命
"Tentacles: Eight Legs, Eight Lives"
可你只有四条腿
But you only have four legs
还外加俩胳膊咧
And two arms
啊对
Oh, yeah
加起来就八条了
Yeah, that makes eight
第一章
Chapter 1
我年纪轻轻就才华横溢
"In my youth, my brilliance was evident
那时我并没有浪费时间交朋友
"Instead of wasting my time making friends
而是创作艺术
I made art
我还记得自己画了幅复杂爪绘图
"I recall making
a rather sophisticated tentacle painting
就连我的老师
that even my teacher--"
等一下
Wait a minute
我一点都没困
I'm not getting sleepy
只觉得无聊
I'm just getting bored
一片茫然
"--and perplexity
眼睁睁看着我因成就而得奖
as I was bequeathed an award for my achievements"
起码我的水管能让他睡着
Well, at least my pipe works for him
要是没法变困
If I'm not sleepy
那就得累坏自己
I'll just have to tire myself out
有热狗
A hot dog
给我
Give me
几天后
给我
Give me
抓到了  你这小老头
I've got you now, you little old man
要看我孙子孙女的照片吗
You want to see a picture of my grandkids?
嗨  派大星
Hi, Patrick
还是睡不着吗
Still not sleeping, huh?
怎么看出来的
How can you tell?
直觉而已
Just a hunch
看来得让睡魔来看看你才行
Looks like you need a visit from the Sandman
他会朝你眼睛吹睡眠沙
He'd blow a little sand in your eyes
然后你就能一下子睡过去了
and you'd be out like a light
睡魔
A Sandman
眼睛  一下子睡过去
Eyes, out like a light
好吧
OK
再见
See you later
我来做个睡魔
Me make Sandman
好  睡魔先生
OK, Mr. Sandman
快朝我眼睛吹睡眠沙  让我睡着
Now blow sand in my eyes and put me to sleep
怎么了
What's wrong?
还要沙子吗
You need more sand?
给我回来
Get back here
先抓到我再说
You'll have to catch me first
酷啊  有个疯子
Cool, a raving lunatic
我要把你追到天涯海角  睡魔
I'll chase you to the ends of the ocean, Sandman
终于啊
Finally
这就对了
That's it
多来点
Keep it coming
你要去哪
Where are you going?
我还没困呢
I'm not sleepy yet
快啊
Come on
再来
More
你要去哪
Where are you going?
好点了
Better
可我还要
But I need more
睡魔  你的破烂睡眠沙一点用都没
Sandman, your stupid sleep sand doesn't work
派大星  住手
Patrick, stop
那不是睡魔
That's no Sandman
是章鱼哥
That's Squidward
回忆录又要加一条不幸遭遇了
Another misadventure for my memoir
一点用都没有  海绵宝宝
It's no use, SpongeBob
什么睡魔睡眠沙完全没法让我变困
All the Sandman's sand couldn't make me sleepy
我这后半辈子只好一直清醒了
I guess I'll just be awake for the rest of my life
如果说你要永远清醒下去
If you're going to be awake forever
那就可以好好利用一下  从中受益
then you might as well put that to good use
海绵宝宝  还真是
SpongeBob, you were right
我可以一直醒着  正好就能
My "awakeyness" makes me the perfect
通宵当个长途卡船司机了
all-night long-haul trucker
收到  好兄弟
10-4, good buddy
好  请安全驾驶
All right, keep your rubber side down
把挡风玻璃的虫子清理掉
and the bugs off your glass
我们等会再见
I'll catch you on the flip